Finding Aid for the Lacy Jr, Charles Lockert, Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Notes and revisions for introduction to Moot Plays of Corneille. Holograph and typescript. Folder 2. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to La Mort de Gompee. Typescript carbon. Folder 3. (Folder 11)
- La Mort de Pompee. Typescript. Folder 4. (Folder 11)
- Notes for Pompee. Typescript. Folder 5. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to He radius, Gtypescript carbon. Folder 6. (Folder 11)
- He radius. Typescript. Folder 7« (Folder 11)
- Notes for Geraclius. Typescript. Folder 8. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to Don Sanche d'Aragon. Typescript carbon. Folder 9. (Folder 11)
- Don Sanche d'Aragon. Typescript. Folder 10. (Folder 11)
- Notes for Don Sanche d'Aragon. Typescript. Folder 11. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to Attila. Typescript carbon. Folder l8. (Folder 11)
- Attila. Typescript. Folder 19. (Folder 11)
- Notes for Attila. Typescript. Folder 20. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to Pulcherie. Typescript carbon. Folder 21. (Folder 11)
- Pulcherie. Typescript. Folder 22. (Folder 11)
- Notes for -Gulcherie. Typescript. Folder 23. (Folder 11)
- Introduction to Surenax pescript carbon. Folder 2b. (Folder 11)
- Surena. Typescript. Folder 25. (Folder 11)
- Notes and worksheets for Surena. Typescript. Folder 26. (Folder 11)
- N.B. All folders in Container 12 are manuscript materials for More Plays by Rivals of Corneille and Racine. Vanderbilt, 1968. (Folder 12)
- Drafts of Preface, Contents and Dedication for More Rivals. Typescript. Folder 1. (Folder 12)
- Alexandre Hardy: Mariamne. Xerox. Folder 2. (Folder 12)
- Pierre Du Ryer: Esther. Xerox. Folder 3. (Folder 12)
- Revisions from Du Ryer: Esther. Typescript and holograph. Folder (Folder 12)
- Tristan l'Hermite: La Mort de Seneque. Xerox. Folder 5. (Folder 12)
- Tristan l'Hermite: Osman. Xerox. Folder 6. (Folder 12)
- Jean Rotrou: Saint Genest. Xerox. Folder 7* (Folder 12)
- Thomas Corneille: Maximian. Xerox. Folder 8. (Folder 12)
- Thomas Corneille: Ariane. Xerox. Folder 9« (Folder 12)
- Claude Boyer: Oropastes. Typescript fragment. Folder 10. (Folder 12)
- Philippe Quinault: Astrate. Xerox, bolder 11. (Folder 12)
- Pechantre: Ggta. Xerox. Folder 12. (Folder 12)
- Jean-Galbert Campistron: Tiridate. Xerox. Folder 13. (Folder 12)
- Jean-Galbert Campistron: Tiridate. Fragments of French typescript and holograph draft. Folder 14. (Folder 12)
- La Grange-Chancel: Ino et Melicerte. Xerox. Folder 15. (Folder 12)
- N.B. All folders in Container 13 are manuscript materials for a projected third book of translations by playwrights of the 17th and ltfth century ne6-classical theater. (Folder 13)
- Notes on projected book of translations. Type script. Folder 1. (Folder 13)
- Philippe Quin&ult: Ia Mort de Cyrus. Fragment of translation, typescript. Holograph notes. Folder 2. (Folder 13)
- Jean-Galbert Campistron: Armlniua. Typescript. Also notes in holograph and typescript. Folder 3* (Folder 13)
- Thomas Corneille: La Mort d'Annibal. Typescript. Folder 4. (Folder 13)
- La Grange-Chancel: Amaaia. Typescript. Folder 5* (Folder 13)
- Voltaire:_Alzir«. Typescript. Folder 6. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: Alzire. Revisions; typescript. Folder 7. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: Mahomet. Typescript. Folder 8. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: Mahomet. First draft and notes. Typescript and holograph. Folder 9. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: Le Fanatisae. Xerox copy from aa unidentified edition of Voltaire's plays. Possibly used as a comparative text for Mahomet translation. Folder 10. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: erope. Typescript. Folder 11. (Folder 13)
- Voltaire: Merope. First draft and notes. Typescript and holograph. Folder 12. (Folder 13)
  This is a name index of the correspondents of Charles Lacy Lockert, Jr. The figure in parentheses immediately following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection; the dates are for the time of the letters. The full name of the writer is given whenever possible. The last number given refers to the box and folder in which the correspondence may be found.
Index of Incoming Correspondents
____________________Eleanor,(1); 30 June 1919; 1-3.
Anderson, Harriet,(l); 11 December 1952; F. 1-6.
Allen, Louise,(2); 25 April 1956, 30 November 1956; F. 1-7.
Applewhite, Ted,(l); k March I960; F. 1-9. (Enclosures Picture of Mt. Knauss, F. 1-16.)
Bailey, Herbert S., Jr.,(9); 13 February 1951*, 2 April 1951*, 9 April 1954» 3 May 1954, 20 May 1954, 10 Septemberl954; F. 1-6. 7 December 1956; F. 1-7. 29 January 1957, 22 November 1957; F. 1-8.
Baldwin, T.W., (l); 8 February 1959; F. 1-9.
Bevan, W.L.,(l); lgf February 1922; F. l-f.
Boylan, Marion,(l); 2k June 1922; F.
Branscomb, Harvie,(l); 23 August 1957; F. 1-8.
Brown, J. Trevor,(l); 23 November 1956; F. 1-7.
Bryant, William H.,(2); 15 August 1959, 26 August 1959, (3 enclosures); F. 1-9.
Cohane, Tin (?),(l); 11 October 1951 (to Mrs. Gilbert Troxell); F. 1-6.
Davis, William Steams, (3); 11 December 1922, 31 December 1922; F. 1. 23 January 1925; F. 1-5.
Downer, Alan,(l); 16 January 1957; F. 1-8.
Eager, Mrs. George B., (Bess),(8); May 1953; F.l-6. 2 October 1957
F.l-8. 19 February 1959, 6 March 1959, 11 March 1959. 25 March 1959$ 26 March 1959; F. 1-9. 29
December 1961; F. 1-10.
Falk, Eugene H.,(3); 11 May 1956, 29 October 1956, 2 December 1956; F.l-7.
Finch, Mary A.,(l); 23 February 1922; F. 1-k.
Gaines, Camaie Pendleton (Mrs. Charles Kelsey),(3); 2 June 1922, 25 June 1922; F.l-Jf. 23 April 1926; F. 1-5.
Gaines, Charles Kelsey,(22); 22 May 1921, 22 December 1921; F. 1-3. 21
February 1922, 5 March 1922, (enclosure), 6 March 1922, 19 March 1922,(enclosure), 30 March 1922, 12 April 1922, 1 May 1922, 16 May 1922,(enclosure), 17 May 1922, 3 June 1922, l8 June 1922, 1 July 1922, 26 July 1922, August 1922, 2k September 1922, 15 November 1922; F. l-Jf. 1 January 1923, 21 March 1923, 11 October 1925; F. 1-5.
Gaines, Chloe S. (Mrs. Clarence Hurd),(l); 3 June 1922; F. 1-k.
Gaines, Clarence Hurd,(l9); 2 January 19Mf (telegraa), 29 October 1951, 11 July 1953
F. 1-6. l*t October 1955, 26 November 1955, 26 December 1955, 22 February 1956, 27 March 195$J F. 1-7. 16
July 1957, 11 August 1957, 27 January 1958, 17 December 1958; F. 1-8. 18
February 1959, 13 March 1959, 6 June 1959, 9 June 1959; F. 1-9. k January 1961, l8 January 1961, 15 March 1961; F. 1-10.
Hall, Flem,(l); 5 January 1957 (to George Leonard); F. 1-8.
Halaey, Frank D.t(l); 26 November 1935i F. 1-5.
Hawkes, Jans,(l) 22 February 1922; F. 1-4.
Henry, Louise,(l); 24 January 1922; F.l-4.
Houston, Benjamin F.,(3); 5 December 1955» H May 1956, 19 November 1956; F.l-7.
Kellenbfcrger, Hunter,(6); 1 January 1946, 10 February 1952, 20 April 1953, 26 September 1953, 20 April 1954; F. 1-6. 19 August 1970; F. 1-10.
Littell, A.J.,(l); 5 August 1953; F.l*6.
Long, Percy V. (Modern Language Association), (2); 16 April 1937» 1 December 1937; F. 3-18.
McDavitt, Clareace G.,(3); 30 September 1952, 20 October 1953; F.l-6. 5 February 1955; F. 1-7.
McGrew, John B., (l); 16 February 1922; F. 1-4.
--------Emily, (E.G.M.),(l); 30 April (1956?); F. 1-7.
Mabry, Mallnda,(l); 25 March 1922; F. 1-4.
Meltom, Catherine Parker,(2); 30 September 1957, 25 November (1957); F.l-8.
Miller, Frank L.,III,(l); 1 February 1958 (enclosure); F. 1-8.
Miller, Frank L.,Jr.,(2); 19 February 1946, 29 March 1954; F. 1-6.
More,Paul E.,(l); 20 March 1923; F. 1-5.
Nash, Robert C., (typist),(8); 29 November 1948, 10 Apr ii 1952, 27 October 1953, 20 December 1954; F. 1-6. 17
January 1955. 17 February 1955, 12 January 1956; F. 1-7. 21 September 1965; F. 1-10.
North American Review,(l); 6 January 1920; F. 1-3.
Parrott, Thomas Marc, (4); 13 February 1944, 27 January 1946; F. 1-6. 11 January 1956; F. 1-7. 9 January 1959 (card); F. 1-9.
Perria, Bernadott®,(l) 30 December 1903 to Charles Kelsey Gaiaes (enclosure ia letter from Gaines, 19 March 1922); F. 1-4.
Pierce, Louise, (l); 8 January 1946 (enclosure); F. 1-6.
Ramsay, Franklin,(l); 21 June 1915 (telegram); F.l-3.
Ramsay, Mebane,(l); 13 April 1959; F. 1-9.
Ramsay, Nelle,(49); August 1908, 20 August 1908 (card), 23 December 1908 (Christmas card), May 1909 ( ommencement Invitation), August 1909t 6 January 1910, 16 March 1910, 26 April 1910 (card), 26 April 1910 (card), 27 April 1910, 6 June 1910 (card), 16 November 1910, 30 December 1910 (card), 31 December 1910 (card); F. 1-1.
12 March 1911, (l?) April 1911 (card), 5 June 1911, 5 July 1911, 17 July 1911, 20 August 1911 (card), 6 September 1911* 23 December 1911 (card), 13 January 1912 (enclosures), 8 Apr ii 1912, 19 June 1912, 2 August 1912, 14 August 1912, 16 August 1912, 22 August 1912 (card), 7 September 1912, 13 September 1912, 19 September 1912, 30 September 1912, 14 October 1912, 22 December 1912, 27 December 1912; F. 1-2. 2
June 1913» 19 June 1913, 4 November 1913« (one page erased), 18 December 1913, 28 January 1914, 25 March 1914, 1 June 1914, 21 July 1914, 10 December 1914, 18 January 1915; F. 1-3.
Robinsoa, Nelsoa L.,(l); Copy, n.d. F. 1-5* Russell, Bob, (l); 2 January 1957 (to George Leonard); F. 1-8. Shafer, ,(l); 17 October 1922; F. 1-4.
Sinnen, Jeanne,(l); 31 January 1957; F. 1-8.
Sloaae, William,(3); 15 November 1956, 10 December 1956; F. 1-7. 7 January 1957? F. 1-8. Troxell, Janet Camp,(2); 8 October 1951 (to Clarence McDavitt); F. 1-6. 31 March 1956; F. 1-7.
Wade, Ira 0.,(l); 23 February 1954; F. 1-6.
Weyand, Colonel A.M.,(2) 29 December 1956; F. 1-7. 2 January 1957; F.l-8. Whaney, J.B.t (l); 2 February 1922; F. 1-i.
Wilsoa, Robert H.,(2); 20 May 1957, 12 October 1957; F. 1-8.
Youag, James N.,Ct); l8 September 1952, 20 April 1953; F. 1-7. 16 June 1956, 19 November 1956; F. 1-7.
Correspondence is listed chronologically. Folder is indicated by the abbreviation F..1908: ___August to Nelle Ramsay; F. 2-1.
INDEX OF OUTGOING CORRESPONDENTS
1913: ___November to Nelle Ramsay; F. 2-1.
1915: 23 June to Frank Ramsay; 2k June to Me bane Ramsay; F. 2-1.
1921: 18 May to Charles Kelsey Gaines; 2 December to Charles K. Gaines; F. 2-1.
1922: 12 January to Charles K. Gaines; Reply to March 30 of Charles K. Gaines; 7 December to William Stearns Davis; Reply to 11 December of William S. Davis; F. 2-1.
1936: N.D. to Gilbert Murray (book inscription); N.D. to Gilbert Murray; F. 2-1.
1937s 28 April to Christian Gauss; N.D. to Christian Gauss; F. 2-1.
1938: _____January to Dr.(Percy) Long, (MLA); 9 March to Dr. Percy Long; F. 3-18.
1943: (Fall) to Thomas Marc Parrott; F. 2-8. 5 December to Charles K. Gaines; F. 2-2.
1944: Reply to telegram of 2 January of Clarence Hurd Gaines; N.D. to Clarence H. Gaines; N.D. to Clarence H. Gaines; N.D. to Clarence H. Gaines; N.D. to Canon Watson; F. 2-2. (15 February) to Thomas Marc Parrott; N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott; N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott (fragment); ( December) to Thomas M. Parrott; 29 November to John Heard of Poet Lore (fragment on reverse of preceding letter to Parrott); F. 2-8. c.1944-
1945: N.D. to Clarence H. Gaines; N.D. fragment probably to Clarence H. Gaines; N.D. to Eleanor; F. 2-2. N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott; N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott (fragment); F. 2~8.
1945: N.D. to Grosset and Dunlap; Unidentified fragment on reverse of Grosset and Dunlap (subject: Corneille); 7 December to Mrs. (Louise) Pierce; F. 2-2. N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott; N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott; N.D. to Canon Watsoa (fragment on reverse of preceding letter to Parrott; F. 2-8. c.1945-
1946: N.D. to Mrs. (Louise) Pierce; F. 2-2.
1946: N.D. to Hebane Ramsay; F. 2-2. Reply to 27 January to Thomas M. Parrott; (Fall) to Thomas M. Parrott; (Fall) to Thomas M. Parrottj December to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8.
1947: January to Me bane Ramsay; F. 2-3. January to Ghoaas M. Parrott; TJanuary-February) to Thomas M. Parrott; (January-February) to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. 15 March to Gilbert Murray; F. 2-3. (March-April) to Thomas M. Parrott; (Spring) to Thomas H. Parrott; (Spring) to Frank Miller III (on reverse of (°pring) letter to Parrott); August to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. November to Canon Watson; N.D. to Mrs. (Louise) Pierce (two letters on same paper); N.D. to Canon Watson; F. 2-3.
1948: (Winter) to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. N.D. to Canon Watson; F. 2-3.
1959: N.D. to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. 1950: (June) to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. c.1950
1951: Unidentified correspondent; topic: Chief Plays of Corneille Ms. F. 2-3.
1951: 10 February to Dr. Harold C. Bfadley; May to Mr. (Clarence) McDavitt; 23 July to A.G. Graham; July to Tim (Subject: Shakespeare); N.D. to Dr. (Christian) Gauss; N.D. to Dr. (Christian) Gauss; N.D. to (Clarence) McDavitt; F. 2-3. N.D. to Thomas M; Parrott; F. 2-8. N.D. to Datus C. Smith (fragment); N.D. to Dr. (J. Duncan) Spaeth; N.D. to (James) Young; F. 2-3. c.1951-
1952: N.D. to (Clarence) McDavitt; F. 2-3.
1952: N.D. to Mr. ______ Burkhart; Unidentified correspondent; topic: Theory of the Novel; F. 2-3.
1953: 12 March to Princeton University Press; 21 September to President Gordon K. Chalmers; 31 October to Herbert S. Bailey; 12 November to Herbert S. Bailey; N.D. to Princeton University Press, (plus typed fragment of same); F. 2-k.
1954: 8 February to Herbert S. Bailey; 13 February to Ira 0. Wade; 15 February to Herbert S. Bailey; Reply to 2.Ap*iiLiof Herbert S. Bailey; 3 December to Herbert S. Bailey; F. 2-4.
1955: 29 September to Bob Nash; F. 2-4.
1956: Zb January to Herbert S. Bailey; Enclosure for 3 February to Mr. (Clarence) McDavitt; l'f March to Jim (James N. Young); Harch ta-Hfara. Gilbert Troxell (Janet Camp Troxell); March to Mrs. GilbertTroxell; (October-November) to H.S. Bailey; (October-November) to Mrs. Houston; Two letters N.D. attached to the Bailey and Houston notepaper above: l) Mra. Cottrell, 2) Thomas M. Parrott; 7 November to Dr. H.C. Nixon (Vanderbilt Press, two copies); 25 Govember to (William) Sloane; 8 December to Dean Taylor (Holograph original on back of 3 February McDavitt above); 12 December to (William) Sloane; 17 December to Herbert S. Bailey, typescript and holograph; December to (William) Sloane on reverses<5f December Bailey holograph; _ December to Editor of the Romanic Review on reverse of 17 December Bailey holograph; N.D. to (T.W.) Baldwin (Holograph of 23 November Sloane on same notepaper); N.D. to Frank L. Miller, Jr.; N.D. to The Dante Society of America; F. 2-5*
1957: 5 January to Herbert S. Bailey; N.D. to Editor of the Romanic Review (on same notepaper as 5 January Bailey letter); N.D. to (William) Sloane (on reverse of 5 January Bailey letter<>; N.D. to Mr. (Eugene H.) Falk; N.D. to Miss (Jeanne) Sinnen; 25 January to Herbert S. Bailey (Holograph and typescript); 29 January to H.C. Nixon; 4 February to (William) Sloane (holograph and typescript); February-March to (Eugene H.) Falk; February- March to Herbert S. Bailey (on same notepaper as preceding Falk letter); Reply to 20 May of Robert H. Wilson; May to Thomas M. Parrott (on reverse of preceding Wilson letter); Reply to 12 October of Robert H. Wilson; N.D. to Jane; F. 2-6. April to Thomas M. Parrott; F. 2-8. c.1957-
1958: N.D. to Leonard J. Wang; F. 2-7.
1958: 21 November to Rob Roy Purdy; N.D. to Mebane Ramsay; F. 2-7.
1959: 21 August to William H. Bryant; 31 August to Santa Barbara Cemetery Association. (Attn. W.A. Bryant); 25 November to Director of the Vanderbilt University Press; F. 2-7.
I960: Reply to k March of Ted Applewhite; F. 2-7.
1965: 17 November to Alida (Alida Sima Malkus); F. 2-7. Unidentified fragment. Topic: Corneille's The Cid. F. 2-7. N.D. to Miss (M.F.) Stawell. Topic: Translation of Faust. F. 2-7.
Printed materials removed from the Charles Lacy Lockert, Jr. papers include the following: 1).1) Thermofax copy of:
1) Thermofax copy of: Vondel, Joost van den (1587-1679) Vondel's Lucifer, translated by onard Charles Van Nappen. N.Y.: Continental Publishing Co., 1898.
This vas a thermofax copy of pp. 263-438. ere were no markings on the text to indicate any relationship of this work to the writiags or translations of La.c.y Lockert.
2) Newspaper clippings:
Nashville Banner 7 December 1936, PP. 3-6
9 December 1936, PP. 15-16
10 January 1937, PP. 7-10
30 September 1958, p;..lJ
1 October 1958, P. 8
2 October 1958, P. 10
Nashville Tenaessean 10 January 1937
September 1947, PP. l-2, 11-12
9 September 1948, p.19
10 September 1948, p.23
13 September 1948, P.7
12 November 1948, P. 21
4 March 1949, PP. 25-26
4 March 1949, p. 2
17 July 1952, P. 15
5 August 1952, P. 9
Des Moines Register 4 November 1948, PP. 1-2
12 December 1948, PP. 1-2, 15-16.
New York Sun 28 October 1948, pp.29-301 47-48
Gainee Family
Absalom Graves Gainee President of St. Lawrence University, Cantoa, N.Y., 1872-1888. After that period returned to faculty as Professor of Psychology, a post he held until the early 1900's.
Charles Kelsey Gaines 1854-1944
1875-1876 Tutor at St. Lawrence
1876 Graduated from St. Lawrence;4ppointed acting professor of Greek
1877 Appointed Professor of Greek
1878 Married Cammie Pendleton Woods, five daJs after her graduatioa from St. Lawrence.
1882 Appointed Professor of English
1884-1893 Librari8.Jl at St. Lawrence
1886 rote college song.
1892 Honorary doctorate froa Lombard..1896-1900
Left St. Lawrence fcrone year of travel, Greece, Egypt. Then vas Vice-resident of Bacheller Syndicate (Publishiag endeavor of I1Ving Bacheller, another St. Lawrence alumnus) and also on staff of Nev York World.
In 1900 returned to St. Lawrence. The dates of his M.A. from St. Lawrence and an honorary L.L.D. froa St. Lawrence are not clear. Total career at St. Lawrence spaaned the yeare of 1876-1931, with the four years out from 1896-1900 noted above. Retired as Professor of Greek and English.
Clarence Hurd Gaines Only son of Charles Kelsey Gaines. Married to Chloe s. Gaines, had one soa, Richard Hurd Gaines. Undergraduate degree from St. Lawrence, graduate study at Harvard. No dates on any of this available. Editor of Harper's Book Shelf (dates?) Wrote all revieve for North American Review from 1912-? Chai+li8.D. of the English Department, St. Lawrence University, c. 1922.
All of this biographical information comes froa 118. sources ia JUL, i.e. the correspondence of Charles Kelsey Gaines (22 letters), Cammie P. Gaiaes (2 letters), Clarence Hurd Gainee (19 letters) and Chloe s. Gaines (1 letter). There is also a biographical sketch and tribute is the introduction .. to An Angel' a 1 a novel edited and seen through publicatioa by Lacy Lockert after the death of Charles K. Gainee. Undoubtedly St.. Lavrence university could furnish much information about this family if it is ever necessary in connection with the manuscripts of Charles Kelsey Gaines in the Lockert collectionl)
1) Gorgo: Romance E.f Old Athene. Illustrated by George Variaa. Boston: Lothrop, Lee Shepard Co., 1903. (Later publication continued b.J Groeset & Dunlap, Nev York after the bankruptcy of the original publishers.)
2) Authorized Revision of Cushing's Manual., l916.
3) Sixty Years of St. Lawrence, Canton, N.Y., .19l6.
4) An Angel's Diary Canton, N.Y.: St. Lawrence University, 1962. Printed tor St. Lawrence by the Parthenon Press, Nashville, Tennessee from the 1921 manuscript by Lacy Lockert.)